Southwest Folklore Center Cassette Recordings Collection, 1975-1995
University of Arizona Libraries, Special Collections
- Lalo Guerrero: Spanish versions of pop tunes, Lalo Guerrero, CONTENTS: [side A] Así Como el Sol -- Un Amor -- Tennessee Waltz -- Si Yo Fuera Rey -- Llora el Corazón -- Si Dejarás que te Amara -- Sé Mi Amor -- Llorar -- Llegaste Tarde -- El Bolerito de la Main -- [side B] Rag Mop -- La Cosa -- La Tamalada -- Tiro de Mulas -- Nel Blue de Pinto de Blue -- Chicas Patas Boogie -- Vamos a Bailar -- Los Chucos Suaves -- Marihuana Boogie -- Muy Sabroso Blues. Source:Lalo Guerrero; SWF 97.21/C.3
- Lalo Guerrero: rancheras from the 50's and 60's, Lalo Guerrero, CONTENTS: [side A] La Burrita -- La Mula Bronca -- Tiro de Mulas -- El Barzon -- Tenochtitlan -- El Sonorense -- Tu Solo Tu -- Prieta Linda -- Malagradecida -- La Borrachona -- El Quemado -- Dinero Robado -- El Lavadero -- Mi Gusto Es -- [side B] Corazón Burlado -- Se Llama Lupe -- Ya No Puedo Querarte -- Cantineando -- Pobre Corazón -- Malagradecida -- Tonto Corazón -- Ya Volvió el Soldado Razo -- Cananea -- Ella -- Ella y Yo -- Tu Injusticia -- Por Eso Me Vez Borracho -- La Que se Fué. Source: Lalo Guerrero; SWF 97.21/C.4
- Lalo Guerrero: more rancheras from the 40's, 50's and 60's, Lalo Guerrero, CONTENTS: [side A] Dime corazon -- Canasta Uruguaya -- De nada me valió -- No -- Siempre, siempre -- Canta corazon Copa tras copa -- La culebra pollera -- Noches de angustia -- Nube gris -- El cochinito -- La flota de los burrachos -- La novia perdida -- Corzaon, corazon -- Porque presumes -- Ni tu ni yo -- [side B] Mi guerita -- Me pagas mal -- Pobrecita -- Nomas por ti -- Corazon burlado -- Se llama Lupe -- Elena -- Yo soy el bato. Source: Lalo Guerrero; SWF 97.21/C.5
- Trio Imperial de Lalo Guerrero, Trio Imperial, CONTENTS: [side A] Balaju -- Mi ranchito -- El caiman -- Mi pueblo natal -- La mancornadora -- La pachuquilla -- El pachuco -- Juan Charrasqueado -- El hijo de Juan Charrasqueado -- El presidiario 13 -- Siempre traes a tu mama -- Pa luego es tarde -- Y nada pasó -- El trenecito -- Los dos carnales -- Mujeres de los 40’s -- El lavaplatos -- [side B] El pachuco y el Tarzan -- Maldita suerte -- Las comadres -- Las mujeres -- La vida del soltero -- T’en cuidado -- El bracero -- La boda de los pachucos -- Mi burrito -- El tirilongo -- Mi guerita -- Chicana -- Me lleva el tren -- El conquistador. Source: Lalo Guerrero; SWF 97.21/C.6
- Lalo Guerrero with the Mariachi Colonial, Lalo Guerrero, CONTENTS: [Side 1] Battle cry of the Chicano -- [side 2] Himno chicano. Source: Lalo Guerrero; SWF 97.21/C.7
- Experimental Music Instruments 10:3 (March 1995), Chesley Goseyun Wilson, 1995 March; Cassette tape to accompany Experimental Music Instruments 10:3 (March 1995) [includes performance on the "Apache violin" by Chesley Goseyun Wilson]. Source: Chesley Goseyun Wilson and Ruth Longcor-Harnisch Wilson; SWF 97.22/C.1
- Un corrido del chupacabras, Tracy Duvall, Corrido written and performed by Tracy Duvall. Source: Tracy Duvall; SWF 97.23/C.1
- El chupa cabras, Los Brillantes del Norte, Cassette tape of the first song on the “El chupa cabras” CD by Los Brillantes del Norte (Alacrán ARCD-1064). Source: James S. Griffith; SWF 97.25/C.1
- Corridos y tragedias del la frontera, part 1-2 (Arhoolie/Folklyric C-7019-7020), Source: James S. Griffith; SWF 97.26/C.1 [pt. 1], SWF 97.26/C.2 [pt. 2]
- Early classic recordings, 1950-1955, Lalo Guerrero, CONTENTS: [side A] Manzanita -- Mambo mambó -- La Cosa (la continuación) -- Mambito -- Mambo Guajiro -- Para para la rumba -- No me vuelvo a enamorar -- Soñando esperaré -- Florecita -- Llorar -- Llegaste tarde -- [side B] Chicas patas boogie -- Muy sabroso blues -- El bolerito de la main -- La tamalada -- Se fue y me dejó -- La burrita -- Tiro de mulas -- La mula branca -- El sonorense -- El burrito. Source: Lalo Guerrero; SWF 97.30/C.1
- Papa's dream by Los Lobos and Lalo Guerrero (Music for Little People 9 42562-4), Los Lobos with Lalo Guerrero, CONTENTS: [side A] La bamba -- Wooly Bully -- Buzz, buzz, buzz -- Route 90 -- Corrido for Papa Lalo -- La Bicicleta -- Cielito lindo -- [side B] La Mañanita alegre -- El pato -- De colores -- La Mañanitas tapatias -- La piñata -- La, la, la -- La bamba -- Wooly bully banda (reprise). Source: Lalo Guerrero; SWF 97.30/C.2
- Borderlands: from conjunto to chicken scratch: music from the Rio Grande valley of Texas and Southern Arizona, CONTENTS: [side A] La cuquita -- Gregorio Cortez -- Aunque me odies -- Un rato no más -- Un adobe y cuatro velas -- Mi unico camino -- Angel de mis anhelos -- Corrido de Gerardo Gonzáles -- El saino de Donna, Texas -- Dados cargados -- [side B] Caso perdido -- La calle flores -- Quedate -- San Javielpo Chu’kuy Kawi -- Ali oidak polka -- Old Man Rooster -- Madre mia chote -- Uwaldina y Juan Gonzales. Source: Washington, D.C., Smithsonian/Folkways Recordings (SF 40418); SWF 97.33/C.1
- Interview with Yefim Levitskiy conducted by Florence Aronson, 4/5/97, Yefim Levitskiy; Florence Aronson, 1997 April 5; Taped interview intended to accompany her paper for ENG 248B, Spring 1997 (97.38/M.1). Source: Florence Aronson; 97.38/C.1
- Interview with Tsyiya Levitskaya and Rita Levitskaya conducted by Florence Aronson, 4/13/97, Tsyiya Levitskaya; Rita Levitskaya; Florence Aronson, 1997 April 13; Taped interview intended to accompany her paper for ENG 248B, Spring 1997 (97.38/M.1). Source: Florence Aronson; 97.38/C.2
- Interview with Nellya Sare conducted by Florence Aronson, 4/18/97, Nellya Sare; Florence Aronson, 1997 April 18; Taped interview intended to accompany her paper for ENG 248B, Spring 1997 (97.38/M.1). Source: Florence Aronson; 97.38/C.3
- Interview with Yelena Levitskaya conducted by Florence Aronson, 4/27/97, Yelena Levitskaya; Florence Aronson, 1997 April 27; Taped interview intended to accompany her paper for ENG 248B, Spring 1997 (97.38/M.1). Source: Florence Aronson; 97.38/C.4
- Corrido de Manuel Pacheco; Despedida al Presidente Pacheco, Celestino Fernández, Guillermo Sáenz, Two corridos written by Celestino Fernández, music by Guillermo Sáenz, for Manuel Pacheco, University of Arizona president, 1991-1997. Source: University of Arizona Library Special Collections; 97.47/C.1
- There is a time, Kibbey Family, 1 sound cassette, stereo; Cassette donated by the Kibbey Family of Tucson, Arizona; bluegrass and bluegrass gospel performing group; children and grandchildren of banjo and guitar player Coy Kibbey “who has a Friday evening jam session in Catalina” [JSG note].Contents: Side A: I’ll be with you -- I believe in the old time way -- There is a time -- Over in the Gloryland -- Dark Hollow -- Shuckin’ the corn -- Side B: Tell them about Jesus -- Live beyond the grave -- Ashokan farewell -- Judgment day -- House of gold -- Old Joe Clark. Source: The Kibbey Family; 97.51/C.1
- La Llorona, Christopher Rodarte, Cassette of music for film entitled La Llorona: a ghost story, written by Christopher Rodarte; performed by Tish Hinojosa, Mariachi Trio Tariacuri; Nelson Martinez con Mariachi Campanas de America. All songs repeat once. Source: Christopher Rodarte; 97.52/C.1
- “Pulse of the Planet” radio broadcasts, James S. Griffith, 1 sound cassette, stereo; Cassette tape of four short (ca. 3 1/2 minutes) radio broadcasts produced by “Pulse of the Planet” for the American Museum of Natural History. The programs are narrated by James S. Griffith and deal with the Fiesta de San Francisco in Magdalena, Sonora. Source: James S. Griffith; 97.64/C.1
- Corridos de Sonora, Sept. 27, 1990, Antonio Federico [et al.], 1990 September 27; 1 digital audio tape, stereo; Recorded music session featuring musicians: Antonio Federico, Frank Moreno, Paul Romero, Alfonso Molina. Also Richard Morales and James S. Griffith. Session recorded by Jack Loeffler, Santa Fe, N.M. This cassette is the master for 97.65/C.2. CONTENTS: Rafaelita (corrido) -- José Lizardo (corrido) -- La Yegua Colorada (corrido) -- El General Santa Cruz (corrido) -- Valente Quintero (corrido) -- [polka] -- De Colores -- Cristo Rey -- Viva Sequin -- [polka]. Source: James S. Griffith; 97.65/C.1
- Corridos de Sonora, Sept. 27, 1990, Antonio Federico [et al.], 1990 September 27; 1 sound cassette, analog, stereo; Recorded music session featuring musicians: Antonio Federico, Frank Moreno, Paul Romero, Alfonso Molina. Also Richard Morales and James S. Griffith. Session recorded by Jack Loeffler, Santa Fe, N.M. This cassette is the working copy of 97.65/C.1. CONTENTS: Rafaelita (corrido) -- José Lizardo (corrido) -- La Yegua Colorada (corrido) -- El General Santa Cruz (corrido) -- Valente Quintero (corrido) -- [polka] -- De Colores -- Cristo Rey -- Viva Sequin -- [polka]. Source: James S. Griffith; 97.65/C.2
- Rancheritos del Sur, Rancheritos del Sur, 1 sound cassette, analog, stereo; CONTENTS: Side A: El tunel de Aguaprieta -- Solo unos puños de tierra -- De una vez por todas -- Yo tambien soy de huaraches -- Vacas de a kilo -- La blazer blindada -- Roberto Tapia -- Un indio quiere Llorar -- Side B: El padre y el hijo -- El mafioso mojado (written by Leonardo Yañez) -- Que caro salio quintero -- Por los caminos del norte -- Los hermanos Castillo -- Decepciones y placeres -- Tu te lo buscaste/La sorpresa. Source: Circulo Musical CCM 4006; 97.66/C.1
- Corridos famosos, 1 sound cassette, analog, stereo; CONTENTS: Side A: Luz Elia de Chihuahua -- El Zorro Garcia -- Un preso mas -- Un mal padre -- La muerte de un asesino -- El rey de Sinaloa -- Dario Ibarra -- Dos hacendados -- Side B: El nuevo Jinete -- El contrabande de Juarez -- El puma -- Buscando venganza -- La traicion de Lupita -- Contrabande de Sonora -- El as y el grano de oro. Source: Joey International 9020; 97.66/C.2
- Todos los corridos del 1991: los mejores artistas norteños, v. 3, 1 sound cassette, analog, stereo; CONTENTS: Side A: Tragedia de Killeen / Region Norteña -- Corrido del muñeco / Los Rieleros del Norte -- El tunel de Agua Prieta / Los Jilgueros del Arroyo -- Tres muertes de Valerio / Los Bebeldes del Bravo -- Doble Traicion / Los Gatilleros de Durango -- Contrabando y dolor / Los Braveros de Peñas -- Side B: Contrabando en la frontera / Los Rieleros del Norte -- Onesimo aranda / Los Jilgueros del Norte -- El chuma / Los Astros de China -- Tragedia de Nicanor / Los Palmeros de San Carlos -- El corralon del paso / Los Sheriffes del Norte -- La muerte de Susana / Region Norteña. Source: Joey International JGS-9024; 97.66/C.3
- 15 corridos famosos / con Los Rangers, Rangers, 1 sound cassette, analog, stereo; CONTENTS: Side A: Cirilo reyes “El Cuervo” -- Traiciones politicas -- Los valientes de Sonora -- Juan Bedoya -- La camioneta gris -- Jacinto Treviño -- El gato -- Corrido de Chuy Menendez -- Side B: El guaraque -- Las tres mujeres -- Los tres amarradores -- La carga blanca -- El mano negra -- La tragedia de las pilas -- El cañon Johnson. Source: [Los Rangers] RAN 002.; 97.66/C.4
- 20 corridos famosos / con los mejores grupos de Sonora, v. 2., 1 sound cassette, analog, stereo; CONTENTS: Side A: Pancho Lopez / Grupo Los Lujman -- Elpidio Pazos / La Proyección Musical -- Juan Ramos / Dueto Sensación -- Modesta ayala / Los Rangers -- Corrido de Don Simon Perez / Dueto Sensación -- Corrido de Octavio Norzagaray / Los Principes del Norte -- El profugo de Sonora / Los 5 Texanos -- Los valientes de Sonora / Los Rangers -- La tragedia de Ures / Grupo Los Lujman -- Corrido de la guarilama / Raices de Sangre -- Side B: El cométa y el potrillo / Los Rangers -- El grullo y el saino / Grupo Los Lujman -- La cabra y el hechichero / Los Originarios de Sonora -- Corrido de “El fariseo” / Grupo Los Lujman -- Corrido de custodio / El güero León con Banda --Corrido de “El Alambrado” / Sonora Band -- Corrido de “El criminal” / Proyección Musical -- Corrido de “Los 9 valientes” / Los 5 Texanos -- Canto a Sonora / Nacho Beltrán con Banda -- “Canto a la paz” (Puerto de ilusion) / Los Rangers. Source: Arriola [no number].; 97.66/C.5
- Early Classic Recordings, 1950-1955, Lalo Guerrero., 1 sound cassette, analog; Privately produced cassette “compiled by Mark Guerrero.”; 97.67/C.1
- Global Rhythm Radio, 8/14/97, Lalo Guerrero: an evening of conversation, memories and live performance with the father of Chicano music, Lalo Guerrero., 1997 August 14; 2 sound cassettes, analog; Tape recording of radio transmission on 8/14/97, on KXCI 91.3 FM, Tucson, Arizona.; 97.68/C.1-C.2
- Tune learning tape, Southern Arizona Old Time Fiddlers Association, 1 sound cassette, analog, 1 7/8 ips; Contains tunes for learning songs. Each song is performed once slow, and once at normal speed. Source: James S. Griffith.; 98.12/C.1
- Song about Magdalena de Kino, Sonora, Jorge Olvera [source]; Trio Coral, 1 sound cassette, analog, 1 7/8 ips; Song obtained by Jorge Olvera of Mexico City, performed by Trio Coral. Griffith states that it could be considered a corrido, but it is atypical. This version taped for Griffith by Olvera, possibly from a commercial recording. Source: James S. Griffith.; 98.13/C.1
- Cowboy memories from Mayer, Marvin Bennet and Ray Gardner, 1991 November 27; 1 sound cassette, analog, 1 7/8 ips; Recorded before a live audience November 27, 1991, at the Wishbone Restaurant, Mayer, Arizona. Accession sheet (SWF 009, 98.14/M.1) lists contents. Source: James S. Griffith.; 98.14/C.1
- Arizona Sonora corrido project recordings, James S. Griffith and Jack Loeffler, 4 sound cassettes, analog, 1 7/8 ips; 1 sound cassette, digital (DAT); Playlists and description of recording sessions recorded on four cassette copies, of recordings intended for the Arizona Sonora corrido project "to be issued by Smithsonian Folkways and cosponsored by the SWFC." Session logs on two typed pages are at SWF 009, 98.15/M.1. Source: James S. Griffith.; 98.15/C.1-C.5
- The way we play it, Busted Cowboy Band, 1 sound cassette, analog, 1 7/8 ips; Commercial cassette of recordings by the Busted Cowboy Band. Source: James S. Griffith.; 98.17/C.1
- In Loving Memory of Mrs. Rosie Johnson - Southside Presbyterian Church Choir - Tucson, Arizona, Vol II, Southside Presbyterian Church Choir - Tucson, Arizona., 1 sound cassette, analog, 1 7/8 ips; Commercial cassette recording of the Southside Presbyterian Church Choir in Tucson, Arizona. Recording date unknown. The recording is dedicated to the memory of African American gospel singer Rosie Johnson who was a featured performer at the Tucson Meet Yourself festivals in the 1980s and 1990s. CONTENTS: Side A: O It Is Jesus -- I Love to Praise Him -- Twelve Gates -- We Shall Walk -- Swing Low, Sweet Chariot -- Lift Him Up -- Lead Me, Guide Me -- Love Has No Borders -- Side B: You Must Be Born Again -- Call Him Up -- Mother’s Amazing Grace -- There’s A Bright Side -- Up Above My Head -- Wade In The Water -- Be Not Afraid. Source: James S. Griffith.; 99.2/C.1
- Los Riberenos del Golfo, Los Riberenos del Golfo, 1 sound cassette, analog, 1 7/8 ips; Commercial cassette recorded in Bahia Kino, Sonora as part of the Arizona/Sonora Corrido Project by Jack Loeffler and Jim Griffith in January 1998. CONTENTS: Side A: Sonora Querida -- El Canal del Infiernillo -- El Corrido del Guasiado -- Tololoche Chicoteado -- Recuerdo de Amor -- La Yaquecita -- Side B: La Barca de Guaymas -- Cielito Lindo -- Solamente Una Vez -- Volver, Volver -- El Rancho Grande -- Quisiera Amarte Menos. Source: James S. Griffith.; 99.3/C.1